<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
	<channel>
		<title>Arcanum Caedis | </title>
		<generator>(c) Chulapa Jekyll Theme RSS generator</generator>
		<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis</link>
		<description>Todo sobre Arcanum Caelis</description>
		<language>es-ES</language>
		<copyright>(c) 2025, Arcanum Caedis</copyright>	
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 17:07:08 +0200</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 17:07:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
		<category>blog</category>
		<ttl>60</ttl>
		<atom:link href="https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<title>Arcanum Caedis | </title>
			<url></url>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis</link>
			<description>Todo sobre Arcanum Caelis</description>
		</image><item>
			<title>Puesto de Avanzada</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><blockquote class="tecnocracia-cita">
  "La tecnología no es una herramienta: es la manifestación de la voluntad de orden sobre el caos."
  <footer class="tecnocracia-cita-footer">— Directiva de la Iteración Central</footer>
</blockquote>

<section class="tecnocracia-section">
  <div class="tecnocracia-posts">
    <article class="tecnocracia-post">
        <p>En el lado opuesto de Arcanum Caedis, el Puesto de Avanzada se erige como el bastión de la tecnocracia, dominado por el Nuevo Orden Mundial. Este puesto de control es el centro neurálgico desde el cual los tecnócratas supervisan y expanden su influencia sobre el plano. A diferencia de la Ciudad Mágica, el Puesto de Avanzada es un modelo de eficiencia y orden, con estructuras de acero y vidrio que reflejan la fría precisión de la tecnocracia. La ciudad es un centro de investigación tecnológica avanzada, donde las ciencias exactas y la ingeniería de vanguardia son el pan de cada día.</p>
        <p>El Puesto de Avanzada no solo está equipado con instalaciones para la creación de tecnologías avanzadas, sino que también utiliza la interacción con entidades y fuerzas en Arcanum Caedis, conocidas como X, para fortalecer su presencia. Estas entidades se mantienen bajo estricta supervisión y son fundamentales para la expansión del control de la tecnocracia en el plano. A través de este proceso de interacción, el Puesto de Avanzada ha logrado integrar una red de comunicación de largo alcance, utilizando antenas de gran potencia para conectar sus instalaciones con otras bases dispersas en el plano, asegurando el control total sobre el flujo de información y recursos.</p>
        <p>A pesar de su apariencia de orden y progreso, el Puesto de Avanzada también está preparado para defenderse de las amenazas que puedan surgir, empleando sistemas automatizados, inteligencia artificial avanzada y tropas de élite que operan bajo un rígido control. El lugar se mantiene como un faro de la tecnocracia, donde la visión de un mundo perfectamente organizado y regido por la lógica y la razón se materializa en cada rincón.</p>
      <a href="#" class="read-more">Leer más</a>
    </article>
  </div>
</section>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250422_puestodeavanzada/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250422_puestodeavanzada/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>La Tierra</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><blockquote class="tierra-cita">
  "La Magia no es una herramienta: es la manifestación de la voluntad superior del alma."
  <footer class="tierra-cita-footer">— Directiva de la Iteración Central</footer>
</blockquote>

<section class="tierra-section">
  <div class="tierra-posts">
    <article class="tierra-post">
      <h2>Torre del Vacío</h2>
        <p>Más blabla de la tierra...</p>
      <a href="#" class="read-more">Leer más</a>
    </article>
  </div>
</section>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250422_latierra/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250422_latierra/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>Blabla Magos</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><blockquote class="concordia-cita">
  "La Magia no es una herramienta: es la manifestación de la voluntad superior del alma."
  <footer class="concordia-cita-footer">— Directiva de la Iteración Central</footer>
</blockquote>

<section class="concordia-section">
  <div class="concordia-posts">
    <article class="concordia-post">
      <h2>Torre del Vacío</h2>
        <p>Más blabla de la concordia...</p>
      <a href="#" class="read-more">Leer más</a>
    </article>
  </div>
</section>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250422_concordia/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250422_concordia/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>Blabla tecnocracia</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><blockquote class="tecnocracia-cita">
  "La tecnología lo es todo."
  <footer class="tecnocracia-cita-footer">— Iteración X haciendo cosas</footer>
</blockquote>

<section class="tecnocracia-section">
  <div class="tecnocracia-posts">
    <article class="tecnocracia-post">
      <h2>Torre del Vacío</h2>
        <p>Más blabla de la tecnocracia...</p>
      <a href="#" class="read-more">Leer más</a>
    </article>
  </div>
</section>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250422_blablatecnocracia/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250422_blablatecnocracia/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>Arcanum Caedis</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><blockquote>
  <p>“Lo que he encontrado es algo que solo podría haber nacido de un sueño trastornado o de un pecado aún mayor.”</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p class="blockquote-footer">Maestro Elian de Vorath, Comandante de la Orden de los Vigilantes del Velo</p>
</blockquote>

<div class="arcanum-post">
<p>
Arcanum Caedis no fue un regalo ni un descubrimiento, sino un error catastrófico nacido del orgullo de los Despertados y la arrogancia de los Iluminados. Una explosión de paradoja, un choque entre magia y tecnología, desgarró el tejido de la realidad, abriendo este plano como una herida en el cosmos. Su misma existencia es inestable, marcada por grietas espaciales que destellan con energías imposibles, una advertencia constante de que este mundo podría colapsar sobre sí mismo en cualquier momento.
</p>
<p>
La Tierra, degenerándose bajo el peso de siglos de guerra, se libró momentáneamente del conflicto cuando los magos y tecnócratas decidieron trasladar su lucha a este nuevo campo. Aquí, en las tierras fracturadas de Arcanum, establecieron sus bastiones. Los magos, maestros de las Esferas, manipulan la esencia misma del plano, levantando torres y murallas que respiran como seres vivos. Los tecnócratas, fieles a su dogma de orden y control, construyen enclaves fortificados donde la maquinaria murmura sus profecías mecánicas.
</p>
<p>
Sin embargo, no todo es conquista organizada. Las escaramuzas son constantes, cada encuentro una mezcla de brutalidad pragmática y desdén ideológico. No se trata solo de quién controla los recursos; se trata de imponer una visión, de demostrar que su paradigma es el único verdadero. En este tablero de guerra, los verdaderos peones son los habitantes originales de Arcanum Caedis.
</p>
<p>
Eran un pueblo sencillo, avanzados hasta los límites de la era preindustrial, con su propia relación con la naturaleza y los secretos del plano. Pero ahora sus aldeas están en ruinas, sus campos marchitos bajo las marchas inclementes de soldados tecnócratas y constructos mágicos. Los pocos sobrevivientes vagan como fantasmas, exiliados en su propio hogar, enfrentando horrores que ni siquiera comprenden mientras las fisuras del plano escupen monstruosidades irreales.
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arcanum_Caedis" target="_blank">Leer más en Wikipedia</a>
</p>
</div>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250416_Arcanum-Caedis/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <category>bootstrap</category><category>demo</category><category>downtown</category><category>edinburgh</category><category>image</category><category>kramdown</category><category>landscape</category><category>trips</category><category>wikipedia</category><media:title type="html"><![CDATA[Arcanum Caedis ]]></media:title>
      <media:content url="https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/assets/img/ArcanumInterna.webp" medium="image"/>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/assets/img/ArcanumInterna.webp" /><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20250416_Arcanum-Caedis/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>The Acueduct of Segovia</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				<h3>20 centuries ago</h3>
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><p>The <strong>Aqueduct of Segovia</strong> (Spanish: <em>Acueducto de Segovia</em>; more accurately, the aqueduct bridge) is a Roman aqueduct in Segovia, Spain. It is one of the best-preserved elevated Roman aqueducts and the foremost symbol of Segovia, as evidenced by its presence on the city’s coat of arms.</p>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20191127_acueduct-of-segovia/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <category>downtown</category><category>image</category><category>landscape</category><category>project-links</category><category>trips</category><category>wikipedia</category><media:title type="html"><![CDATA[The Acueduct of Segovia ]]></media:title>
      <media:content url="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d7/Acueducto_Segovia_noche.JPG/1024px-Acueducto_Segovia_noche.JPG" medium="image"/>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d7/Acueducto_Segovia_noche.JPG/1024px-Acueducto_Segovia_noche.JPG" /><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20191127_acueduct-of-segovia/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>A landing page</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				<h3>With image header</h3>
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><p>A simple landing page with an image on top. Transparencies (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">png</code>) works better on this combination.</p>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20190803_landing-page/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <category>demo</category><category>example</category><category>guest-author</category><category>image</category><category>layout</category><media:title type="html"><![CDATA[A landing page ]]></media:title>
      <media:content url="https://dieghernan.github.io/chulapa/assets/img/site/transparent.png" medium="image"/>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://dieghernan.github.io/chulapa/assets/img/site/transparent.png" /><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20190803_landing-page/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>Urban art</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				<h3>Creativity is everywhere</h3>
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><p>Urban artists can use anything as a canvas to express their art</p>

<p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/8b/Madrid_-_Graffiti_11.jpg/407px-Madrid_-_Graffiti_11.jpg" alt="Grunge is not dead" /></p>

<p class="caption">Picture by <a href="https://commons.m.wikimedia.org/wiki/User:Zarateman">Zarateman</a></p>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20181109_urban_art/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <category>downtown</category><category>image</category><category>street</category><category>urban art</category><media:title type="html"><![CDATA[Urban art ]]></media:title>
      <media:content url="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/8b/Madrid_-_Graffiti_11.jpg/407px-Madrid_-_Graffiti_11.jpg" medium="image"/>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/8b/Madrid_-_Graffiti_11.jpg/407px-Madrid_-_Graffiti_11.jpg" /><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20181109_urban_art/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>Flake it till you make it</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				<h3>Excerpt from Soulshaping by Jeff Brown</h3>
    		<p>2 min.</p>
				<div><p>Under what circumstances should we step off a path? When is it essential that we finish what we start? If I bought a bag of peanuts and had an allergic reaction, no one would fault me if I threw it out. If I ended a relationship with a woman who hit me, no one would say that I had a commitment problem. But if I walk away from a seemingly secure route because my soul has other ideas, I am a flake?</p>

<p>The truth is that no one else can definitively know the path we are here to walk. It’s tempting to listen—many of us long for the omnipotent other—but unless they are genuine psychic intuitives, they can’t know. All others can know is their own truth, and if they’ve actually done the work to excavate it, they will have the good sense to know that they cannot genuinely know anyone else’s. Only soul knows the path it is here to walk. Since you are the only one living in your temple, only you can know its scriptures and interpretive structure.</p>

<p>At the heart of the struggle are two very different ideas of success—survival-driven and soul-driven. For survivalists, success is security, pragmatism, power over others. Success is the absence of material suffering, the nourishing of the soul be damned. It is an odd and ironic thing that most of the material power in our world often resides in the hands of younger souls. Still working in the egoic and material realms, they love the sensations of power and focus most of their energy on accumulation. Older souls tend not to be as materially driven. They have already played the worldly game in previous lives and they search for more subtle shades of meaning in this one—authentication rather than accumulation. They are often ignored by the culture at large, although they really are the truest warriors.</p>

<p>A soulful notion of success rests on the actualization of our innate image. Success is simply the completion of a soul step, however unsightly it may be. We have finished what we started when the lesson is learned. What a fear-based culture calls a wonderful opportunity may be fruitless and misguided for the soul. Staying in a passionless relationship may satisfy our need for comfort, but it may stifle the soul. Becoming a famous lawyer is only worthwhile if the soul demands it. It is an essential failure if you are called to be a monastic this time around. If you need to explore and abandon ten careers in order to stretch your soul toward its innate image, then so be it. Flake it till you make it.</p>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20150226_flake-it-till-you-make-it/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <category>manuscript</category><category>random</category><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20150226_flake-it-till-you-make-it/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>Test markdown</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				<h3>Each post also has a subtitle</h3>
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><p>You can write regular <a href="http://markdowntutorial.com/">markdown</a> here and Jekyll will automatically convert it to a nice webpage.  I strongly encourage you to <a href="http://markdowntutorial.com/">take 5 minutes to learn how to write in markdown</a> - it’ll teach you how to transform regular text into bold/italics/headings/tables/etc.</p>

<p><strong>Here is some bold text</strong></p>

<h2 id="here-is-a-secondary-heading">Here is a secondary heading</h2>

<p>Here’s a useless table:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Number</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Next number</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Previous number</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Five</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Six</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Four</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Ten</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Eleven</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nine</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Seven</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Eight</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Six</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Two</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Three</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">One</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>How about a yummy crepe?</p>

<p><img src="http://s3-media3.fl.yelpcdn.com/bphoto/cQ1Yoa75m2yUFFbY2xwuqw/348s.jpg" alt="Crepe" /></p>

<p>Here’s a code chunk:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>var foo = function(x) {
  return(x + 5);
}
foo(3)
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And here is the same code with syntax highlighting:</p>

<div class="language-javascript highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">foo</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">x</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="k">return</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">x</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">);</span>
<span class="p">}</span>
<span class="nf">foo</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20150220_test-markdown/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <category>exciting-stuff</category><category>markdown</category><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20150220_test-markdown/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>To be</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				<h3>… or not to be?</h3>
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><p>To be, or not to be–that is the question:
Whether ‘tis nobler in the mind to suffer
The slings and arrows of outrageous fortune
Or to take arms against a sea of troubles
And by opposing end them. To die, to sleep–
No more–and by a sleep to say we end
The heartache, and the thousand natural shocks
That flesh is heir to. ‘Tis a consummation
Devoutly to be wished. To die, to sleep–
To sleep–perchance to dream: ay, there’s the rub,
For in that sleep of death what dreams may come
When we have shuffled off this mortal coil,
Must give us pause. There’s the respect
That makes calamity of so long life.
For who would bear the whips and scorns of time,
Th’ oppressor’s wrong, the proud man’s contumely
The pangs of despised love, the law’s delay,
The insolence of office, and the spurns
That patient merit of th’ unworthy takes,
When he himself might his quietus make
With a bare bodkin? Who would fardels bear,
To grunt and sweat under a weary life,
But that the dread of something after death,
The undiscovered country, from whose bourn
No traveller returns, puzzles the will,
And makes us rather bear those ills we have
Than fly to others that we know not of?
Thus conscience does make cowards of us all,
And thus the native hue of resolution
Is sicklied o’er with the pale cast of thought,
And enterprise of great pitch and moment
With this regard their currents turn awry
And lose the name of action. – Soft you now,
The fair Ophelia! – Nymph, in thy orisons
Be all my sins remembered.</p>
</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20150213_hamlet-monologue/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <category>manuscript</category><category>wikipedia</category><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20150213_hamlet-monologue/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
		</item><item>
			<title>Fanáticos</title>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[	
 				
    		<p>1 min.</p>
				<div><blockquote>
  <p>“Cita súper importante sobre las naciones de los fanáticos”</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p class="blockquote-footer">Explicada por un lunático cualquiera o algo por el estilo pero con acento.</p>
</blockquote>

<section class="arcanum-section">
  <div class="arcanum-posts">
    <article class="arcanum-post">
      <h2>Torre del Vacío</h2>
        <p>En las ruinas de un antiguo observatorio, los magos descubrieron una fisura que canta en sueños...</p>
      <a href="#" class="read-more">Leer más</a>
    </article>
  </div>
</section>

</div>
				]]>
			</description>
			<link>https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20150115_pirates/</link>
			<category>posts</category>
		    <category>Arcanum</category><category>Naciones</category><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jmesquerdo.github.io/arcanumcaedis/20150115_pirates/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
		</item></channel>
</rss>